const history = [
    {
        number: "1",
        question: "As recently dramatised in a critically acclaimed miniseries, what year did the Chernobyl disaster occur?",
        answer: "1986",
        hint: "The space shuttle challenger is destroyed this year"
    },
    {
        number: "2",
        question: "Who was Lord Mayor of London four times between 1397 and 1419, and the inspiration for a classic English folk tale?",
        answer: "richard (dick) whittington",
        hint: "Famous for travelling with his cat"
    },
    {
        number: "3",
        question: "Who was the second President of the United States?",
        answer: "john adams",
        hint: "This president was a leader of the American Revolution"
    },
    {
        number: "4",
        question: "Who was the only one of Henry VIII’s wives to receive a Queen’s funeral?",
        answer: "jane seymour",
        hint: "The third wife of Henry VIII"
    },
    {
        number: "5",
        question: "Which British archaeologist discovered Tutankhamun’s tomb?",
        answer: "howard carter",
        hint: "When Carnarvon asked “Can you see anything?”, Carter replied with the famous words: “Yes, wonderful things!”"
    },
    {
        number: "6",
        question: "Who was the leader of Britain’s ill-fated Antarctic expedition which was one of the first to reach the South Pole in 1912?",
        answer: "robert f. scott",
        hint: "Died on the Ross ice Shelf, Antartica"
    },
    {
        number: "7",
        question: "In which European country was there a civil war between 1946 and 1949?",
        answer: "greece",
        hint: "The capitol is Athens"
    },
    {
        number: "8",
        question: "Which 13th Century Scottish knight did Mel Gibson portray in Braveheart?",
        answer: "william wallace",
        hint: "Quoted to have said: Every man dies, not every man truly lives."
    },
    {
        number: "9",
        question: "Which war was fought in South Africa between 1899 and 1902?",
        answer: "second boer war",
        hint: "Between the British Empire and two idependent states"
    },
    {
        number: "10",
        question: "In which country did the Second World War Battles of El Alamein take place?",
        answer: "egypt",
        hint: "The capitol is Cairo"
    },
    {
        number: "11",
        question: "Who discovered the wreckage of the Titanic?",
        answer: "robert ballard",
        hint: "Passed away ages 78"
    },
    {
        number: "12",
        question: "What year did the Challenger Space Shuttle disaster take place?",
        answer: "1986",
        hint: "This year the Chernobyl Nuclear Disaster happened"
    },
    {
        number: "13",
        question: "What year was the Magna Carta signed?",
        answer: "1215",
        hint: "This is a royal charter of rights agreed by King John of England"
    },
    {
        number: "14",
        question: "Which British King suffered from a stammer, as portrayed by Colin Firth in The King’s Speech?",
        answer: "king george vi",
        hint: "A 2010 film called the kings speech depicted this King's struggle with speech"
    },
    {
        number: "15",
        question: "What was the name of the ship that brought news of the Battle of Trafalgar to Britain?",
        answer: "hms pickle",
        hint: "Originally a civilian vessel, then purchased and used by the royal navy"
    },
    {
        number: "16",
        question: "Which pilot famously fought in the Battle of Britain with two artificial legs?",
        answer: "douglas bader",
        hint: "He was credited for 22 aerial victories"
    },
    {
        number: "17",
        question: "When did the Korean War end?",
        answer: "it didn’t – an armistice was signed in 1953 but the two countries are still technically at war",
        hint: "The famous 38th parrellel is home to a stand off even today"
    },
    {
        number: "18",
        question: "Which famous American expolorer was born in Scranton, Pennsylvania?",
        answer: "hugh glass",
        hint: "Depicted in the 2015 movie the Revenant"
    },
    {
        number: "19",
        question: "Which vessel is famous for having the bloodiest mutiny in the Royal Navy's history?",
        answer: "hms hermione",
        hint: "This name was later to be given to a Leander-class frigate"
    },
    {
        number: "20",
        question: "Who discovered penicillin?",
        answer: "alexander fleming",
        hint: "This man was Scottish physician and microbiologist"
    }

];

export default history;